if you'd like to join me in just a quick
little 90 second body scan meditation
just a quick check and don't call it a
meditation just checking in on your
senses here we go get present in your
physical senses feel your shirt and your
pants against your skin
feel where your breath is coming from
underneath your nose and your diaphragm
down below your belly
feel your physical tension in your body
where are you holding are you holding in
your shoulders
what are your feet against the bottom of
your shoes feel like what do your feet
against the floor feel like what is your
body against the chair or whatever
you're sitting on or leaning up against
what does that feel like tune into your
senses
what do you hear far away what do you
hear right here
can you listen without judgment
can you see what you're seeing not just
directly in front of you but the top
left of your vision the top right of
your vision the bottom right of your
vision the bottom left of your vision
whole thing do you see it all
can you quickly taste what's in your
mouth
can you taste what's around can you
smell what do you smell in your
environment
how is your mind going can you observe
yourself checking all of those things
if you could very quickly just not out
loud
just in the comfort of your own mind say
hello
and notice
who's the one
who heard you saying hello
and who is the one who said hello
isn't that interesting be right where
you are check your five senses
get present
anyway here's the episode guys
hi everybody Welcome to the John care
love podcast it's me your host Jacob
from the Internet it's the Jill episode
100 baby we made it 100 episodes here I
am here we are thank you guys so much
for listening how cool is that 100
episodes
um this one the majority of this
specific episode is going to be
um it is a copy of an interview I was
recently on another person's podcast and
this is that conversation so essentially
this man is Brent's Spirit he has a uh
his own podcast called the spiritual
awakening show and we had what's called
a Kundalini conversation his ballpark in
his world
um it's essentially he has conversations
with people who have spiritual
Awakenings you know whether it's
Ordinary People whether it's spiritual
people whether it's people intentionally
doing it or unintentionally doing it
whether they're teachers of it whether
they're someone who is just a completely
regular person who pushed too hard and
had this experience um I fall into the
category of
you know through trauma and depression
anxiety all those sorts of things that
uh I identified with
um you know not so long ago just a few
years ago
I essentially trying to fix all those
things trying to fix myself I more or
less pushed a bit too hard and had
what's called A Spiritual Awakening I
will explain I will break all that down
in the coming episode but I had these um
you know kind of transcendent
experiences these mystical spiritual
experiences that I didn't really know
what I was doing didn't know what I was
getting into
um and um you know it's massively
destabilizing in a lot of ways that's
for sure you know that's why I want to
talk about these things I want to I want
to have them out in the open especially
now that I'm in a place of uh you know
being a lot more firmly on the ground
you know I at least have at least have
one foot firmly on the ground you know
I'm still there's a lot of these things
that I'm still going through I'm still
integrating I'm still trying to
understand them for myself uh you know
like we discussed these Awakening things
there's it's layers and layers of
understand Innings and realizations and
you know these different states of
Consciousness that you can be in that
kind of take some time to integrate um
if you've ever read the work of Eckhart
Tolle he had a spiritual awakening
essentially I mean he had to sit on a
park bench just looking forward for
years just trying to integrate it
there's many
a lot of um you know spiritual leaders
and spiritual teachers you will hear
they had a form of vacundulini Awakening
of a spiritual awakening it's kind of
LED them onto their path now and now uh
you know now whether they're teaching
specific spiritual tactics or not as a
teacher anybody who's had these sorts of
things your life is is drastically
altered afterwards
um there's a sense of
um there is kind of a sense of I know
it's such a heavy word to use in the
first five minutes but it is such a
sense of like a god or not God sort of
um there is a sense of something bigger
than you that's experienced um
um not that it's a capital T truth not
that really anything that I experience
or share is 100 the truth it's just what
I try to communicate as my truth it
seems right to me it seems to be hey
this was my experience uh this seems to
be uh uh an overarching theme to what
happened to me what do you think you
know that's really where I come from
it's a lot of my I'm trying to integrate
my personal actual lived experience over
the last you know half decade or
whatever and correlate it with the
content that I'm consuming with the the
YouTube lectures and the books and the
in the audio books and the podcasts and
the conversations and the just all the
you know everything I see on social
media all these things trying to
integrate my actual experience what am I
really feeling what am I actually going
through in this moment
um and you know on a whole you know
what's what's my overarching story here
what's my
um
what is this like hero's journey that
seems to be being presented to me in
this strange packaging you know how do
you make sense of that how do you move
forward so anyway that's what a lot of
this episode is man it's um it's kind of
me checking in on where I'm at uh Brent
is such a wonderful uh host he really
kind of lets me blab on for quite a
while the first um half this interview
is a lot of me kind of explaining some
some key things that happened to me some
like actual
um hey here's what I did that night to
have a mystical experience um I was in a
blissed out state for a couple weeks
afterwards
um you know and there's so much that I
leave out in here there's so much that I
was trying and doing an experience one
more thing that I mentioned uh uh uh you
know well I guess I suppose two things
there was
you know I'm walking outside and uh as
I'm going to my morning meditation I
just lean over and throw up Brett
mentions that in the beginning here if
you're wondering what he's talking about
this was something that I mentioned in
our conversation together I was
essentially just like in a very
normalized state of what's called
purging I was like getting rid of what
no longer serves me I'd walk to my
meditation cool but I don't need this
anymore go along sit on my meditation
cushion you know hit hit play on the
guided meditation that I'm gonna listen
to or whatever it is among that same
time I had a lot of like strange um
you know I'm not saying that these are
like explainative or these are capital T
truth or these are like
um these are very objective things you
know but I had I would have animals walk
up to me in meditation like be just
within a few feet of me coyotes uh I had
a deer come massively close to me I
would have birds and squirrels like come
right up to me as I'm in these
meditative States or like right as I'm
getting out of them I open my eyes and I
look up and there's like legitimate
Animals by me
um so I just I mean I just had like and
again I know that that like you know so
I'm saying I'm Snow White y'all you know
this is not like that I know how it kind
of goofy all this sort of sounds so
um but I am at a point where I'm just
trying to communicate these things not
in like a
um you know I'm really trying to express
this was my experience I'm not trying to
impose my reality on other people I'm
not trying to um
um you know I'm not really trying to
like stomp out anything you know in
anything other I'm like like I I feel
that there is room for me to share these
sorts of things without me feeling like
I'm bumping into a bunch of walls
without me feeling like I'm pushing
other things out of the way it's very
much yes and it's very much um hey man
like I'm grounded I'm doing well I'm
just normal dude like you you know I
have my own struggles I have my own
um you know things that I work with just
on a day-to-day basis just being a human
I have you know my own neuroses you know
all these things very much there I'm so
much human but also I had these
life-altering experiences
um you know basically when I turned 26
to like you know I guess 30
um that
um or you know nothing short of
fascinating and um
I I think that I will go on uh with as I
continue my life I think I will see
these as definitive moments in my life
like these mystical experiences these
things that I went through these
discoveries that I I kind of got a
glimpse into about
um
like I said my reality and who I am in
the in these sorts of things again I
know as I'm saying this it sounds like
it's like I know something you don't and
I experience something you don't now I'm
special it's not so much that there is
all that but I'm I I'm massively aware
of it and I don't want to come from that
place because I feel like it uh it kind
of muddies the point it kind of muddies
the coolness of this conversation so um
yeah man anyway if you see me on the
street don't uh like I I'm not trying to
share this to be treated a certain type
of way
um I I think that naturally I have like
a you know just my place in with my
friends and with the people that I'm
around I'd like to think that I have
maybe a spiritual tendency to me I think
I have like this loving um thing that I
uh even even before all these spiritual
experiences that seem to be you know in
right relationship with me personally
um and those sorts of things are kind of
Amplified in in a way so
I don't know man
um I uh
I'm just trying to
um you know in integrate and live out
this stuff to the fullest extent of of
my truth and I'm you know I'm trying to
figure out what the heck that means
along the way so that's what a lot of
this at this podcast has been you know
this whole thing has been my mental
health Journey so you guys know that
I've been super open and and uh
explorative about my own insides you
know I've been I've definitely over
shared in so many ways and sometimes
that makes me feel a little a little
like my flanks are wide open like it
makes me feel a little too vulnerable it
makes me feel like I didn't set the
right boundaries with me and even my
audience you know it's like is is open
in in
um uh welcoming I am to really any
levels of conversation I always want to
have room for whatever needs to come up
in that moment there's also um some
difficulty with me sharing these sorts
of things because they are very personal
I still put my foot in my mouth a lot of
it I'm still like man I'm still writing
my journals I'm still typing a lot of
stuff all the time every day and it
still is like I'm not fully
understanding a lot of this stuff I'm
still trying to find my own stable
structure
um
Yeah man so so it's uh I I try to show
up where I'm at but I also feel it makes
me feel that type of way when I over
share too much that's a tendency that I
have over explaining or over sharing you
know here I am this entire intro I could
have said hey this is a conversation
that I had on the podcast enjoy I'll see
you later but here I am 10 minutes later
over explaining these sorts of things so
it's clearly still something that I'm
working through this is now the fourth I
mean the fourth day that I've tried
recording some sort of intro I had a 50
or 40 minute long intro yesterday
um I was having some technical
difficulties and I listened to it back
and I didn't like it and I thought that
I was a little too overly exposed I
thought that
um uh I was trying to like shape the way
that other people see me so I mean
anyway this is all this is all just you
know the the trials and tribulations of
of of my journey as I share it out loud
um just like you know uh ramdas would
say
um you know I've done he would say I've
done 35 years years of intense and deep
meditation practice and I've still never
gotten rid of a single Neurosis you know
you would say that and it's always been
it's such the truth you know like I have
made these legitimate progress you know
I've spent some like serious time over
the last few years and like very
dedicated
um you know you know nearing some level
of monastic states of of thinking and
contemplation and reading philosophical
texts and like just meditating it's just
all this stuff but I'm still you know
I'm still very much from just me you
know I just have my own my own [__]
um uh you know I'm just I'm just a dude
so it's cool anybody is listening to me
so I you know I I guess without trying
to explain it into Oblivion I hope that
you guys continue to hear just that from
me and hopefully that comes from a place
of sincerity as I'm explaining it you
know I'm just
I'm not trying to present myself in any
sort of way I'm not trying to say like
I'm spiritual now I've had these
experiences I'm not trying to say that
I'm some sort of arbiter of anything
that um is uh you know you know none of
these experiences give me they don't
grant me access to anything
um special they don't give me
um you know they don't grant me
permission to say exactly what I want
they don't they don't um
you know I I I I just see that this is
almost like a power Dynamic thing in
some sort of ways you know a lot of
times I'll listen to these on on YouTube
there will be people who will share
their
um here's what happened during my
Kundalini Awakening and a lot of it is
so it's it's very disassociated you know
um I hear that a lot of my own writing
and a lot of my own like poetry and
artistic work too so I have to kind of
balance that myself but like when I hear
other people talk about their Kundalini
Awakening they have this experience a
lot of times it really to me it sounds a
lot like they're coming from they're
still stuck in a victim State this is
something that I'm consistently working
for too you know I'm trying to keep my
mind out of a place where it's a fixed
mindset I want to be growth mindset type
of individual but I also am trying to be
gentle and soft and honest with myself
about where I'm where I'm really at when
I'm really capable of
um uh what I what I need that day how
that matches with my overarching goals
of of you know in my plans for my life
these sorts of things so
um I I don't know I think that I hear so
many examples of other people sharing
their experience having a Kundalini
Awakening as much as I resonate with so
much of it much of it sounds so much
elegant you know I think from an outside
perspective if you haven't had these
sorts of experiences I mean I feel like
this could potentially sound just
massively cringed massively
um you know icky and some sort of
strange way so I hope it doesn't really
hit that hit that vein with anybody
who's listening
um I hope it
um
I hope now that I've over explained it
to Oblivion that now is uh now it goes
down smooth so anyway I have these
spiritual experiences here is an
interview of me talking about them thank
you guys so much for listening to
um you know any any time of my podcast
whether it's the clips whether it's all
these episodes whether this is your
first episode you know welcome thanks so
much I'm gonna keep going I have some
plans to like make this uh actually it's
gonna come into the Forefront of my
priorities here it's kind of one of the
plans that I'm working towards so uh
we're gonna keep going man I have a lot
of cool guests on the on the docket I
have some scheduling things where I want
to do be posting once uh once a week at
a designated time I have some upgrades
coming in the world of audio and like
making in the clips I want to make it to
where all the episodes are
um
transcribed so people can listen to them
without
listening to them if they would like
over on YouTube
I also I recently just did ketamine
therapy I've been going through that
I've done quite a few sessions of that
so I actually I had as much as I had
planned to initially record myself I was
gonna have a video recording audio
recording of me during one of these
sessions because it's a it's a solo
thing that you do at home you have an
eye mask on you basically trip for 90
minutes to two hours and you have these
like massively psychedelic Transcendent
experiences I was going to record myself
but I thought actually after a while
that it may hinder my actual experience
you know here's the thing is I'm as much
as I want to bring everybody along the
way and much as I want to share my
experience because it helps everybody
like I can't muddy the Waters of my
actual mental health because I'm trying
too quickly to share it so that's
something that I definitely have to take
into consideration so yes I did ketamine
therapy
um it's been a couple months now I've
still kind of understanding it I do have
plans to talk about on the podcast to
share with you guys to like explore some
of my experience it was actually pretty
wild doing it by yourself it's a whole
different experience like I'm like
laying on my back dancing with my hands
I'm like humming I'm like beating on my
chest and these drum like crazy patterns
and stuff for massive just for a long
time
um I would I would be like laying there
repeating it's like I am God I love me
like just these kind of like dorky
things
um but uh but yeah it was it was uh it
was it was beneficial it was helpful I
have good reviews for the ketamine
therapy but I do think it's something
that I want to talk about more in detail
um as I understand it myself and I
really want to make sure that I'm in at
a good place for it before I just kind
of like Expose and open up you know all
my listeners to my personal experience
of that you know it just as much as I
love being vulnerable and open and I
really just want to share all this stuff
to help everybody I've also got to make
sure that it's benefiting me to you know
to the max of course so
um
I just got to get to a good place of
that but yeah I uh following that I may
have um uh you know uh I may actually
have the company that I that I went
through to get the ketamine therapy
through who like sends it to the
pharmacy and everything the people that
I talk to like the um you know maybe
call them counselors of sorts
um the people who send me all the
journal prompts all this sort of stuff I
want to review all of it and then
actually get one of those people on the
podcast and have a conversation with
them introduce them as a guest and uh
bring in my own personal experience we
can kind of dissect it maybe talk about
some of the before and afters
um so yeah that's on the upcoming docket
um I have plans to uh more Health stuff
more psychology stuff
um I'm always trying to share what I'm
going through on here I mean like right
now I think a lot of my brain fog these
last few days trying to record these
goddamn intros is um I'm going through
this like parasite cleanse right now I
don't know man I'm just I'm in the thick
of it I'm feeling a lot better I've been
dealing with a lot of um
man the last couple years especially but
really in the last year year and a half
I'm dealing with like a lot of
autoimmune disorders that are really
like kicking my ass
um I'm I'm not very good at
um I feel the need to deal with all
these things on my own and learn about
them on my own so that's just another
another layer of things but yeah man
I've been um a lot of body inflammation
a lot of I deal with like rosacea
stomach issues just all these things
that I'm in in my health along with my
mental health the mental health thing is
when I'm massively depressed I can look
down on my hands and realize that my
hands are inflamed too I get these
bodily inflammation so I'm both trying
to solve these uh you know world of
mental health quarrels through the uh
through the mental as much as I am
trying to solve them through the
physical body so uh sharing more of that
as I discover things as things are
beneficial as things are helpful
I will be coming to the podcast and
sharing those things and once I get more
into the swing of things where I can
have weekly episodes I think it'll be a
lot cooler a lot more
um
a lot uh a lot more direct you know so
people can like just as as I'm going
through things or as I'm trying new
things or as I've gone to conclusions
and really learned things that have
really made me feel them on the other
side of something like I'm on the other
side of this hey this thing was really
kicking my ass for a while it might be
kicking your ass here's what I did now I
feel like this seems to be working I
seem to feel okay you go ahead and give
it a go you know that perspective of
things
um so just just sharing my journey so
there's more of that along the way
coming right up is is more of me sharing
of that and hopefully that episode with
uh
with the people with the ketamines with
the ketamine Peoples Let's Get K hold
baby
I have a lot more plans for the clips I
I don't know you know it's just just
gonna continue going forward and I can't
express enough thank you guys so much
for supporting me for hanging out with
me for being on my side
um for
um you know hey hell maybe even listen
to this just for your own entertainment
and you don't like me that's cool too
man thanks for listening that's a play
button for me man
um if you can hit like subscribe follow
whatever podcaster you're playing on
whether it's Spotify or apple or Pandora
or Amazon or any of those things just
like hit the hit the review give me a
five star give me a whatever
so drop me a comment whatever it is
whatever you see that me doing
if you can interact with it you know I
don't give a [__] if this is heard by
um you know the crazy amounts of people
but uh if you do enjoy it and you do
like it it does help more people stumble
along so if you think it helps as well
interact with it that's greatly
appreciated appreciated this is episode
with Brent spirit and Jacob from the
internet this is me talking about my
Spiritual Awakening that's enough
blabbing for me thank you guys so much
we will see you next time
with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
so a couple questions I forgot to ask
um how would you like me to introduce
you as Jacob Bryans is that your last
name Rhymes is that how you say it yeah
Ryan's or Jacob from the internet
I'm kind of impartial whatever feels
more natural I think Jacob from the
internet includes Jacob Ryan's there's
not my aliases have kind of intertwined
and mixed at this point so
either way okay
okay got it got it and um
Spiritual Awakening Kundalini Awakening
process roughly
how long
um
just so I can give a brief introduction
it's been a certain amount of years yeah
I would say I'm nearly 32 now and it
began when I was 26
um so five six years but of course you
know I I Gotta Throw in once you realize
it seems like it's been going on your
whole life but yeah yeah of course I'd
say about about 26 so five or six years
for me okay okay
cool
all right all set
all right
welcome to another criminality
conversation my guest today is Jacob
Ryan's AKA Jacob from the internet
welcome Jacob thanks so much for joining
us today
yeah thank you man I'm very excited to
talk to you again uh that I really enjoy
our interactions so I'm pumped to be
here man
yeah we recently had a conversation on
your podcast the junkyard love podcast
and admittedly I talked way more than
you did and so my intention today is to
give you a chance to speak because uh
you know during our conversation is was
about my journey but you had sprinkled a
little bit of uh hints and clues about
some of the things that you went through
that sounded really exciting you know
some Kundalini Awakening experiences
since I've begun um I guess in your in
your mid-20s about uh six six years ago
now
um but of course as we were just talking
uh before uh we start a conversation it
seems like for many of us we look back
and our our teens or even our childhood
and we see there's spiritual phenomena
spiritual experiences
if not just spiritual interest was was
clear uh very early on before we even
knew you know what to call it so maybe
we'll get into that today uh you and I I
feel like uh we've got a lot in common
um I see in the background there on your
wall you've got the words turning pro of
course uh that's uh two very powerful
words from one of my favorite authors
and I would say probably my favorite
book ever he's written the war of Art
and I take it it's really influenced you
it's really influenced me as well like I
said uh my favorite book ever and it's
what
got me started in doing this work and so
I'd love to hear about your relationship
with that type of work as an artist
yourself a musician
um very creative person we have here
everybody is Jacob uh spoken word artist
DJ uh you've done some some visual art
as well on your channel there's some
interesting videos and things on your
Instagram and whatnot and so we'll get
into all of that
um so I'll stop talking here and like I
said we're gonna give you the floor take
it away Jacob tell us about your
spiritual awakening journey and from
there we'll tease out some of the uh the
difficulties you face Solutions you
found and any other interesting themes
that come up so how did it all begin for
you
um
well I'm going to kind of start with it
with the the war of art the Stephen
pressfield work I feel like it kind of
ties in so towards the beginning of when
I started going through you know my
Spiritual Awakening was through like
many suffering right
um I just kind of like got to the edge
of who I thought myself to be it wasn't
working out um I was dealing with
massive anxiety depression
um I was actually like
um there's ways in which I would
describe myself as obsessive compulsive
um or just you know overly obsessed
about things that really interest me
there's a way that I got kind of
obsessed with like suicide and stuff
which sounds kind of icky and strange
but I'll elaborate more
um the uh the war of art so
amongst my healing I started reading all
these things and listening to podcasts
and watching YouTube videos and
listening to lectures and somewhere
along the way I heard about the war of
art by Stephen pressfield and it just
kind of like seemed like a cool book and
uh I think that I bought it
I think I bought a physical copy but I
could not get myself to sit down and
read it and I could not I couldn't sit
still long enough to read it but I knew
I really wanted to read it so I ended up
getting it on Audible and I hit play in
my driveway I was like very determined I
was like I want to read this book I was
very like kind of mean to myself at this
moment in my kind of healing Journey
and I was like so mad that I couldn't
sit down and read it so I bought an
audible and I'm a runner I really like
running and so I was like cool I'm just
going to hit play in my driveway and I
don't stop running until I finish this
book
um so it was it was cool because like
you don't even realize how how much that
intertwines with the themes of the book
you know fighting resistance if anybody
else has ever read this book it's uh
you'll understand the correlations but
um yeah so I read it in um it was dude
it was also so profound to me it was
really like putting words on this thing
that
is is common amongst people who are
artists as common amongst creators you
know we have this resistance and you
know our job is to is to
accept the resistance and uh get in
contact with The Muse you know
um and so it just felt it felt very
felt like I kind of won that battle you
know Stephen pressfield talks about how
he uh finally uh found himself like he
wrote a little bit and then he was
washing the dishes and he he was like
whistling as he as he cleaned the dishes
and then he kind of had this moment of
realization like oh I just I just like
did the work you know like I'm at this
this place of Peace doing the dishes
because I did my work that I'm supposed
to be doing
um and so for me as I was running and I
finally finished the book and I was like
oh I just did my work like I found a way
to make it work for me personally like
my version of of uh creating and doing
the work has just been done cool I did
my work for the day I ran and I finished
this book that I was determined to do it
so
um yeah that's the that's the the the
war of our uh which turning pro thing on
my wall is I think the second book in
the the series of sorts with Stephen
Curry the second or third yeah and
that's and that's kind of just you know
like we discussed before Brent was uh it
was kind of like taking your taking your
work serious like dude if you're an
artist if you have these these thoughts
and I ideas you know it's clear that not
everybody else does and so your your
work is to take your work seriously and
do what you got to do like sit down it's
not like you write when you feel like
writing it's you right because you made
a schedule to sit down at 9am every day
that that sort of thing
um which is always is always kind of a
struggle to be natural about your work
as well as uh
be
rigorous you know there's kind of a fine
line between not forcing it not
strangling the art by like I gotta sit
down and finish this thing because
people need to hear it I need to change
the world versus you know just just
doing what you must do
um
so
I had
you know you know we mentioned before we
started recording that um you know a lot
of the Kundalini Awakening stuff the
awake Spiritual Awakening Things Are
as we get through them a few years into
them we start to realize that it's not
really a one moment you know like I
would say that my queen can happen when
I was 26 27 but in retrospect I see how
my entire life has played into it you
know I had um what I would consider
um for a long time I would consider
myself a complete victim of these things
but I had a just a tough childhood man I
just
um
essentially my father got addicted to
like really hard drugs when I was like
eight or nine and it completely crumbled
our family structure I have some older
sisters
um in you know
long story short I ended up kind of like
raising myself in a lot of ways from
those years and so just like the way
that I that I had experienced the world
was like oh dude none of these adults
are taking care of me I gotta take care
of myself
and so the way that I learned to kind of
interface with the world interface with
my life was
um
it really worked for me and it really is
what I needed to do as a young kid in a
Teen
um but as you get older you realize that
the armor you created when you were
younger doesn't serve you going forward
um and so the the structures that I had
created to kind of like
you know let's say spiritually bypass
from from learning from my trauma you
know um they did work for me and and you
know I was successful in certain areas
of my life but as I got older you know
these things
like like this pain of this little kid
who's still hurting inside me starts
beating on the walls from the inside you
know and uh
and yeah so so
essentially when I was when I was 26 my
Kundalini waking was kind of like the
structure of the person that I had built
just didn't like he didn't work anymore
like it just was not working for me the
way that I thought the things I thought
about
um the way that I treated myself
internally was just
um
it wasn't a long-term game for me
um and so I think that
I don't know I I don't want to I was
actually debating on on whether I would
I would explain this part there was kind
of a moment where
in retrospect I can kind of see that it
was almost like the opening moment in in
some senses uh
uh but I actually so I'm a DJ I've been
a DJ since I was
20 I think
um
and just inevitably with the world of
DJing and clubs in in bars and staying
up late and those sorts of things
um you know like partying and drug use
and all this stuff was was part of my
journey
um and I wasn't like really super deep
into it I was kind of the guy who would
like play a little bit along and have a
couple beers sort of sort of thing you
know I've been drunk plenty of times of
course but um the uh cocaine came into
the world
and uh that kind of like
that really like exacerbated my like
self-worth problems inside
and it would just turn into me like
trying to get high to shut up this
internal voice you know to try to this
extreme form of escapism
um and I I had a I had this night I was
in a long-term relationship
I had this night where we were out at
the bar and I was I was cool guy Jake
everybody knows me I play at this bar
all the time the bartenders like ignore
the person in front of them and get my
drink you know this this like ego yeah
man I'm popular here I'm cool this is
like I'm I'm the jock in high school
this is this is my vibe here
um and uh you know people had bought me
shots and so essentially I was like a
little too Tipsy and I got behind the
wheel
um of my car and I had my girlfriend
next to me and I reached into my wallet
and I pulled out this bag of Coke
and I did a key bump and uh it was
interesting because it's like as soon as
I did that like I don't know if I you
know punched my my prefrontal core
cortex in the face or something with
this but it was like I had this out of
body experience when I did this bump of
cocaine and it was suddenly like I was
aware of what I was doing and who I was
and my story and like I was oh this out
of body kind of like uh my higher self
or something going dude what are you
doing
and it was this really loud like I was
like sitting there I was like looking at
my girlfriend
going what am I I'm like drinking and
then doing blow so I could feel a little
bit more sober so I could drive home you
know what what is this what why would I
do this
um and so I think like that seemed to be
a lot of the start of my just extreme
internal self-reflection like I had my
friend come over afterwards and we were
like drinking and doing more blow that
night but the whole time I'm just like
massively aware I'm like miles away from
from being present
and it
I don't know it just like I became
extremely aware of what I was doing and
my influences on other people and uh you
know like even driving behind you know
if you're driving a car and you've got a
car full of people or a car full of
people you love you're responsible for
those people you know if you're if
you're drinking and driving you got
other people in the car like that's your
responsibility if they're hurt and uh
that sort of voice just came incredibly
loud
and so
um
think that
I don't know it kind of turned on this
awareness that I wasn't aware of you
know I was saying it saying a little bit
ago that I was kind of obsessed with
like suicide and like um uh if you ever
have you ever heard of the 27 club in
the world of like Artistry and you know
Kurt Cobain and these artists you know
they um it's like man if my nobody's
really gonna listen to my work unless
I'm dead you know they'll appreciate
appreciate me when my when I'm God you
know and it's this
um
it's this weird like toxic selfish
um uh you're just so unaware of of who
you are and what you bring to other
people
um and so I I guess I kind of just
became massively aware that I was
obsessed with those sorts of things like
I was like oh I just had kind of
accepted I'll be in the 27 club like oh
I guess like this is the year that I'll
probably take my life or next year I'll
probably take my life and uh I started
becoming aware of how crazy that was
like what am I you know I I'm I'm
fantasizing about these things I'm
obsessing about uh how cool it's gonna
be when I'm dead you know like what what
that's so crazy you know um
so uh yeah I I think
it just kind of started this extreme
self-help Obsession like I really just
could not shut off the fact that like
the who I was was not going to work out
for me and that was a legitimate problem
the person that I had created was not
going to be able to continue to go
forward
um
and and I should I should pay attention
to that you know like I shouldn't just
be accepting oh this guy's gonna kill
himself and that's me
um
and so yeah I mean
I continued to
I continued to DJ
um I was still kind of like in that
World
um I just like slowly started to stop
drinking
um I was just less and less drinking um
I stopped partying a lot like I would
stop doing coke I didn't really have any
urge to do it like I didn't really want
to do I had done it a couple times after
that but uh for the most part I didn't
want to do I actually started smoking a
lot of weed just because I was like uh I
had a bunch of sleep issues I was on
antidepressants at this time
um
I just uh I I was I wasn't being being a
good person and so I had all this
internal just noise man I was just so
many layers buried deep beneath this
like cool guy you know
um
and so it's like my
like my structures were breaking but
there was something that happened that
seemed to notice it and take it
seriously suddenly of dude nobody's
gonna save you but you sort of thing
um so I did I guess over the last over
the the coming years after that
um I just got massively more obsessed
with self-help personal growth I always
really like these things like I said I
would kind of been on my own since I was
younger so the things that I had learned
about the world were uh you know in a
way by my own hand like when I was you
know 16 17 I was I was the personal
development section in the library was
my favorite you know I loved all those
things but it was almost like I was
blind to
um uh to a lot of other very obvious
stuff
um and so I would spend a lot of time at
home I would just listen to podcasts and
listen to YouTube lectures and uh I
stumbled into like all these people who
would present the world and present
subjects and present their opinions on
the world in ways that I'd never heard
anybody speak before or you know there's
a there's this group of people uh it's
kind of like a tongue-in-cheek thing but
they were deemed the intellectual dark
web have you heard of this it's uh Sam
Harris Joe Rogan oh okay so yeah yeah so
so it says World these of these guys and
they kind of like accidentally named
themselves and it's like I said a little
bit tongue-in-cheek but um
Sam Harris uh Joe Rogan Brett Weinstein
Eric Weinstein and just kind of like
everyone in their vicinity they're like
uh public intellectuals let's say and uh
man my YouTube my YouTube algorithm was
just feeding me that stuff that I was
listening to I mean I get to the point
where I was
um uh somehow I was lucky enough to to
have like extended periods of time off
of work uh where I maybe do like one gig
a week or I would have like a couple
months where I wasn't working I was just
in a position to where
um I could spend a lot of time listening
to these different uh perceptions of
reality and the different views on on
things that I either hadn't thought of
before or I thought I knew a lot about
but I hadn't really sat and thought
about it much you know I would at that
time I would consider myself uh uh just
use a steal a phrase from a friend of
mine uh read uh he says self-diagnosed
self-diagnosed agnostic he says
um and I would consider myself that I'm
like or an atheist or something I'm like
okay you're all y'all are weird like you
really think that there's a magic man in
the sky with with a beard and whatnot
like that was my very simple
understanding of it but I would listen
to I mean 12 to 14 hours of YouTube a
day in audio books and lectures and I
started like buying my own books that
was
um after a while that out when I was
able to actually read them sit down and
read them
um
and it started making me think about the
world a lot differently of course I was
smoking smoking a lot of weed I mean
and I
I know that I don't know if you you
dealt with this um or if you think about
this way it seems like when I mentioned
smoking weed and like how intertwined
this is it almost feels a little
disregarding to to the complexity of the
of the story it's like oh dude like are
you sure you weren't just super stoned
all the time it is in some ways yes you
know in some ways that was uh a way for
me to actually allow these things in and
kind of penetrate the you know the
person I thought myself to be
um but it would help me kind of like sit
and expand on these ideas
um so I would just I would listen to
Listen to lectures
um
and then I think
inevitably we stumble into meditation
right you know like if you're trying to
heal if you have anxiety depression like
well have you tried meditation and
there's these meditation apps and
there's all this all this stuff this
whole world of self-help um and it
brought me into meditation but the way
that I work is uh
I'm like very extreme about things you
know like I said like I get I get overly
obsessed with stuff and
um you know like the way I've read that
that book for the first time was cool
I'm not going to stop running until I
finish this book and so that kind of
turned into my mindfulness and
meditation Journey
I became super obsessed and extreme
about to where
um I'm listening to these lectures and
it's like the second this lecture is
over or this this YouTube video or this
podcast or whatever okay cool time to go
meditate and I would meditate for hours
and hours a day and I was learning about
meditation I was learning about
um the self and I was doing you know
vipassana and I was doing all these
various different kinds I started doing
a ton of yoga
um
I just
started I mean it was it's like extreme
mindfulness you know I was in this
perception of being aware of who I was
and what my actions were and how I how I
reacted what I am in this world and what
it means to be a part of infinity itself
and just I was in that realm just
hardcore just that's all I would think
about so I would talk about uh my poor
girlfriend at the time they would like
I I would it's funny because I would
think that she was understanding because
I'm so obsessed with what I'm thinking
about at this time of course I think
she's understanding what I'm talking
about and then after a while she would
start to say I don't know what you're
saying I don't know what you're like
what are you what are you talking about
which um was actually kind of like
painful painful in the moment because I
suddenly realized
oh dude I am you know I'm detached from
reality and the reality that I'm
obsessing about and thinking about is
completely distant from this person
um
so
I I guess I guess I just got I was able
to
so over the course of the season I think
the my like Kundalini Awakening was from
intense pushing like this extremely you
know I'm using this fifth phrase extreme
mindfulness which sounds so dorky but
it's kind of what it was it was just I
kept pushing I was like I gotta heal I
gotta get better like I gotta figure
this out and then it's like like why do
I hate myself what is the self what is
self you know like these things and I
would just follow these strings of
thoughts and just pulverize myself with
them just think about nothing but it and
just write about it and record videos of
myself talking about it and just uh try
to like research it and um
so I
I had mentioned in our podcast the other
brand that I had this moment where um
you know because with Kundalini
Awakening we talk about is something
that you're really great on your Channel
about expressing that I love is uh it's
not always this explosion of energy
through the top of the head you know
it's not always uh again I'll bring it
up like you said a snake coming out of
your butt
um it just made me laugh when you said
that but um it's for me I think kind of
like of course like that night where I
had done like a bump of cocaine kind of
brought me this crazy awareness but then
I had a other couple other few moments
that I think that could be uh very
easily intertwined with what we can call
Kundalini Awakening I had one where
um I was listening to this guy Greg
Braden
um he's uh he's like friends with Joe
dispenza
um he's friends with this guy Bruce
Lipton and I've been listening to a lot
of their work and he has he's a musician
and so like a lot of stuff that he he
talks about describes I really resonated
with and he had this brain heart
coherence meditation that I would do all
the time and it plays this certain
frequency you know it's like this 10
minute video or something I found on
YouTube and I'd listen to it plenty of
times before but um it was kind of like
my way of getting centered and
um I would listen to it and he kind of
guides you through this meditation and
it plays a certain frequency and uh
I mean it was the end of the night my my
girlfriend at the time uh we had this
place together we had a house together
and uh she was out of town for a few
days and so I was kind of already in
this mindset of like oh I'm going ham
like you know I don't have to I don't
have to be grounded and talk to my
girlfriend about her day at work that
sounds so selfish and I'm saying it loud
but um it's like I can just go ham on
this this this mindfulness stuff this
this uh exploration of the self stuff
and so I was in that mindset already
like I was going ham I was doing a ton
of breath work I was doing a ton of yoga
that day
um I had meditated for many hours in
that morning or you know I know at least
an hour
um in listening to this brain heart
coherence and I think that I was
actually set I was typing out a sending
a text to my girlfriend kind of about
what I was what I was experiencing is
probably like this complete nonsensical
um you know like something that she
probably didn't understand what I was
talking about but it was it felt
important to me and something about me
typing it as I was listening to this
thing made it very real made it very um
like it jumped from the world of YouTube
into my lived reality and I had this uh
have you ever seen the show Jimmy
Neutron it's a cartoon yeah so who has
these things called brain blasts and he
gets this idea and he's a Brain Blast
and they show this visualization of uh
like the idea going through all his like
neural Pathways and it like makes these
connections and these ideas light up in
different parts of his brain light up
and it was kind of like that like I
experienced something like a Brain Blast
that sounds so so funny to say a lot
um but but what happened is like my my
mind connected to my heart
and I don't know how how to explain it
like I visualized like this
thing this something like dropping down
into my heart and then they were
suddenly connected and then I felt just
like a crazy surge of energy
um and then
dude honestly like the next three days
were crazy I was in this state
um and I think that you've described it
before where I was like stuck in my body
I was I was
I feel so so right now as we're talking
you know I'm not thinking about
breathing I'm not pumping my organs I'm
not pumping my lungs but it felt like I
was suddenly responsible for all those
things it felt like I was
like if I didn't think about breathing I
would stop breathing or something
um you know there's a way where I knew
that wasn't true but it was I couldn't
stop looping about this I was inside my
body
um within an hour I actually like
literally had 9-1-1 up on my phone just
trying to go do I need like am I okay
you know what on Earth is going on
um
well my air conditioning just turned on
is that is that incredibly loud no no
it's all good okay
um if it gets too loud or knowing I can
totally turn it off but um
but yeah so I I I became just Ultra
stuck in my body for whatever that means
and it was funny because I uh I didn't
know what I had done I was like oh I
messed up I did something very uh very
strange here um I was Googling how to
shut my third eye
um that tells you the the information of
how I knew of what I was really doing I
was just pushing
um
excuse me but hang on let me turn off my
air conditioning really quick I'm so
sorry for sure no problem
it's so loud and I don't want it to uh
to harm the recording
but um yeah so uh I I was just in this
state of like being stuck in my body and
I was home alone and I was just in this
complete state of fear um and I think
that that when that happened it kind of
made me again like this other
realization of whoa I'm going hard on
this I'm going crazy intense on this
sort of stuff
um uh in and so you know then I'm
looking for for grounding and I'm
looking for like what is going on I
posted on Reddit
um uh I don't remember what song read it
was maybe like spirituality or something
basically like yo I think I messed up
can anybody help I've been listening to
all these sound frequencies and uh you
know people were sweet enough to suggest
some stuff to to help me get a bit more
grounded but um
so
I
that was certainly a moment um the brain
heart coherence thing was definitely
something that now I think I would
correlate to something to do with
Kundalini like I was moving the energies
throughout my body like suddenly surged
um and then I had to kind of like it
took me a while to kind of
sit with that like I don't know that I
fully snapped out of the being stuck
inside my body thing like I think it
kind of slowly integrated in a strange
way
um in in yoga and breath work and that
sort of thing of course helps but uh
um and then I had a um
I don't know the exact linear time for
all this stuff it's kind of a blur
actually but
um I also had a moment where uh I was
doing a hypnosis like a self-love guided
hypnosis I got like kind of obsessed
with hypnosis for a little while
um and I
I was I was experiencing extreme Bliss
for certain um I was already in this
very blissed out state but then suddenly
I became the color purple and
experienced being The Color Purple
um and I don't know how to explain that
like I just it was I was both liquid and
smoke in the color purple and it was
like this crazy blissed out State and um
I think it in like after that I think I
had a few weeks of being
just light-footed as heck like I was
just blissed out for a while after that
um I also had a moment where I did a
it's not like a past regression but it's
like a I was following some guided
meditation uh I was doing a uh like some
sort of like what is it like child
healing you know like in in healing your
your internal child
um and I had this
essentially I was um I think I was just
to add to the visualization I think I
was doing breath work and yoga naked in
my basement all that day
um it's hilarious to share these things
because it just seems so insane now but
I was doing this like childhood thing
following the meditation
um and I actually saw my younger self
like I saw my teenage self you know I
had mentioned before I had kind of built
up this tough like this is who I need
um you know and then I suddenly like in
my basement
um it's not that I like really thought
physical young person walked into my
basement or anything but I saw my
younger self I hugged him I cried and I
said you did great man I got it from
here
and it was like this you know another
explosion of just healing
um and then I I still don't know what to
make about this part um because I was
listening to a lot of frequencies and
stuff I saw the um
in Hinduism is it Ganesh with the many
arms
many of them have many arms I think
um Ganesh is the uh the elephant uh
elephant face
yeah
um it is is it a a female uh or is there
ganache I think I think Ganesh isn't
male
um female there's there's many actually
um I'm not too familiar with all of them
myself there's uh there's countless
Lakshmi Kali Kali has many arms she's
kind of fierce that's a a common
depiction for Kundalini the divine
feminine but they all are actually all
the feminine ones are for sure
okay yeah because it could it was it was
certainly had a feminine energy
um and it had many arms in a you know
you know I say this I know I sound like
a a bit Daft but uh I didn't know any of
this stuff I didn't know any of these
people I didn't grow up with a religious
or spiritual or any of that you know I I
almost kind of like made fun of that
sort of stuff in a way like um not not
like a mean bullying way but kind of
just in like a all right y'all are like
whatever you want to do but y'all are
crazy about that weird religious
spiritual stuff you know that's just
kind of like my perception of what God
was but um so yeah after I like hugged
my younger self said thank you I've got
it from here then there was this moment
of of experience the many armed God and
it was this feminine thing and again
that put me on another I I would say
like probably a couple weeks if not a
week um of just blissed out you know
it's like I had cleared this very big
blockage or something I know that's kind
of a bit of a strange term when it comes
to like chakras and black chakras and
stuff but um
um yeah and so uh let's say like those
four experiences were kind of my now
that in retrospect they had something to
do with the energy centers in my body
um I would say I would say those were
moments where my Kundalini was um uh
working through me they put me in an
intense blissed out stage afterwards
um which was uh so wonderful in so many
ways and uh but also
because I wasn't grounded at all I mean
I was not trying to be crowded like you
know I was doing yoga and breath work
and stuff and I was walking barefoot
outside and I was doing a lot of running
and working on that sort of stuff
um but just you know I would talk to my
old friends or I would have like
musicians or artists come over and just
looking back like the way that I was
communicating with them was just very
disconnected I was really kind of like
in the state of psychosis I was just a
bit nutty you know and they loved me and
so they accepted like you going through
what you're going through and you know
if I know anything about Jake he's got
this under control
um so there was a lot of that but in
retrospect I see how kind of um
just intense I was you know with all my
relationships and talking to people so
man I would love to uh to pause my
rambling there
um uh and see if you have any any
questions uh for me from there Brent wow
well it's so many common themes uh
between my own journey and that I see
across the board for many others as well
um thank you for sharing
I I just had a conversation with James
dearden bush
and he described something very similar
to what you experienced um you know when
you were uh behind the wheel about to
you know do some cocaine he described
that he as a result of his Awakening had
experienced um an expanded state of
awareness
that
um was unaffected by
him drinking so he got drunk at some
point later
and there's part of him that wasn't
drunk but that was aware that he was
drunk sounds like the same uh State of
Consciousness or same
aspect of your Consciousness that you
had accessed which could look from
almost like an impartial place and say
what the hell is going on here
um even though you're under the
influence and whatnot and that seems to
be
um I've experienced it myself as well uh
it seems to be pretty uh common with
those that experience a sort of uh or we
could call a top-down Awakening or a
crown Awakening and like you said
earlier you know kundalin doesn't have
to rise from the base upward in sort of
explosion
can happen in many different ways and
for me as well my my initial Awakening
was of a very similar flavor to yours
where I had recognized I'm not my mind I
can I can observe my mind so I'm the
Observer and that blasted me open
um
uh and uh that was a major trigger point
of my my Awakening just like you
fascinating stuff there
um
yeah the uh
the healing stuff also super common
right uh super common stuff with the the
inner child and whatnot but even though
I mean Super common amongst those going
through this process I'll put it that
way but uh not that common in general
um
yeah fascinating
why don't you keep going with your story
so
so you're ungrounded or generally
speaking or you're describing some
periods where you're ungrounded
myself as well I mean I can look back
and kind of cringe at the way that I was
uh for sure trying to describe my
experiences or trying to because it was
so novel and exciting I just wanted
other people to experience this with me
and I thought
you know I I have to show them what I
was going through they can hear the
inner child too right you know and and
uh of course you
being young especially uh I I know you
know you're young as well and I guess
you know we are still relatively young
some older people might think we uh we
still don't have a clue what's going on
but
um you know it's exciting and it's good
that at least you had some friends that
said hey you know Jake uh Jake's got out
of control whatever's going through
he'll go through it it'll be okay I mean
not everybody has that some people
you know their their uh Circle will say
you need to uh be be put in a straight
jacket and it happens to many people
um so talk to us a little bit about what
happens
following these periods of intense
Awakening and healing and I guess we
call energetic instability
um where do you go from there
yeah
um
man it's so interesting it's a
because it's like almost still going on
in a way it's almost like still uh you
know my um you know not not like the the
turmoil and the confusion and the um the
non-grounded nature of of exploring
these things but uh I mean I think since
then dude I'm just so again like I said
I've always been really I've really been
interested in kind of the the Realms of
psychology since I was young
um kind of the Realms of uh you know
having a growth mindset not a fixed
mindset you know I said I really like
the self-help section when I was younger
I always loved that sort of stuff but uh
now it's like
I'm just massively uh I don't want to
use the word obsessed like as if I've
you know cured myself of being obsessive
about things but I'm just it's like so
much of what I think about is identity
and self and uh personhood and uh
psychology anthropology uh philosophy I
mean I I
um you know in a lot of my Artistry work
a lot of my poetry work I kind of uh
this sounds a bit self-grandials but uh
I kind of like to consider myself a
philosopher and not a philosopher who um
you know I don't have a degree I didn't
go to college for any of this sort of
stuff but um you know not a philosopher
that studies all the great philosophers
and could tell you everything that Freud
tells you uh like I I like the practice
of philosophy itself like how do you
philosophize your life how do you know
what just the philosophy of self you
know um this is like super uh sure
obsessed with those sorts of things so
I've kind of remained in that realm you
know I I I consume a lot of podcasts I
consume a lot of audiobooks I consume a
lot of books uh interest I contemplate a
lot I do a lot of meditation still
um it's it's a bit more grounded
um it's not like the only thing I think
about I don't go into every single
interaction in my regular life and try
to get people to think about it
um what's actually very cool I will say
is
um
I I show up and I I play the game you
know you know rundas has this way of
saying um uh uh you know you're
you're you're in school why don't you
take the curriculum you know um uh he
had a disembodied being tell him that
and basically that's like um you know
before Enlightenment shop would carry
water after Enlightenment shop would
carry water and it's this uh you can't
go into everyday life like I still got
to pay bills I still got to work
um and and most people don't think about
this stuff at all you know I would say I
don't know what 98 of people 95 of
people or something aren't in this realm
so if you go to work and you're just
trying to like talk about spiritual
enlightenment or um like hey man you
know you don't really exist right you're
like what you know it it makes you feel
more disconnected from people and so a
lot of the last few years have been
almost like my integration back into the
into the world of uh of just just being
with other people and and loving people
for exactly who they are not who I who I
wish they could be and if they could
just see Infinity like I see then they
would really understand and they could
heal all their childhood trauma like you
said and
um uh so
where I'm at now
um
I mean I mean I mean I'll say that
in a lot of ways my life kind of did
fall apart after all of that
um and I hate to say that and like freak
anybody out who's going through um in in
any any sort of uh their Journey right
now and and just uh uh you know bear
with me on on this story here but the I
was in a relationship we were together
for 10 years
um thought we were gonna have kids and
get married and those sorts of things we
kind of just decided like it was this
weird like disassociative state but we
kind of just suddenly decided that um
like that isn't the route that we're
gonna go and we're gonna split up and so
that was just like before I knew it I'm
packing my stuff and I'm like what the
hell what is going on and then we would
have conversations and we're breaking up
the dinner table
it was very very civil you know uh this
woman is is so wonderful we had you know
for all of our lack of communication we
had some wonderful communication as well
um in retrospect these were you know
really such a gift of 10 years with this
person like we had just an incredible
relationship such a fun time
um but it was more of
it was almost like this thing was
working through me and I'm like saying
these things out loud and almost again
observing myself saying them like is
this really what I want like it but it
was it's almost like I was noticing that
I was following my intuition in a very
real way like what needed to happen in
that moment was this breakup was this
okay it's time for something new in my
life like it's time for the next chapter
um but I also was aware of my like I
don't want to leave this person this is
safe I like this person I like this here
my life is cool here but there was also
just this awareness that this isn't this
isn't for me anymore you know I've grown
out of this um in a uh you know not in a
better like I'm I'm higher than you
um but just in a I'm no longer in
alignment with this and so in order to
follow my intuition for it in order to
follow my gut and this this needs to
happen um and it was weird so I'm living
in Austin Texas now um I was living in
Washington state then this was during
the pandemic and uh my work where I make
my money has been as a DJ an audio
engineer I have an audio engineering
degree
um which is actually kind of like a
funny degree nobody really respects it
it's like this dorky like it's almost an
embarrassing thing to say yeah I've got
an anthropology degree
people think it's uh it's archeology and
I don't even correct them anymore
dude that's so funny you mentioned that
I just talked to somebody yesterday who
who confused The Who conflated those two
and I just okay that's what you're gonna
find fossils
um
uh yeah but uh
um and so so I wasn't working
um and so I was at this place where um I
was still I was still pretty out of it
in some senses like during the breakup
um there was still like I would have
days of of uh you know bouts of of
depression where I was just you know
feeling so sorry for myself and
um it was just really hard for me to
stay focused
um you know I was still I still wake up
every morning and you know listen to
ramdas and do my meditation and yoga and
breath work and all these sorts of
things but I was still just like it was
like I was doing those things just to
survive through my day you know I was
going through a lot of turmoil this
breakup was really tough on me
um but yeah for whatever reason as we're
sitting there at the dinner table uh
with with my ex-girlfriend I was like
well I have to move I have to move and
it was one it was like I was hearing
myself say it go why what what are you
talking about
um I was like I well I need to move you
know I'd never moved out of that town my
whole life
but for whatever reason I just had this
extreme
um
intuitive thing that I needed to move
and then I end up going going uh living
with a friend for a few months and he
basically pulled me aside he's just such
a wonderful guy but uh he basically said
look me and my wife his wife we're gonna
move within the next year why don't you
come live with us we'll just charge you
you know we'll be chill on the rent
um get you back on your feet and just
wherever we move why don't you come
along and I was like all right bet and
uh you know so some we landed in Austin
Texas which uh from a creative
standpoint you know
um uh you know Artistry and all these
other things I had followed a lot of
people who had moved to Austin
um I was I was really drawn by like the
Artistry and the music scene and stuff
so it was cool so that's that's where
I've landed now is in Austin
um it's been really fun
um but uh
I guess I'll
I mean I'll backtrack a little bit I had
already started my podcast
um I'm at like 100 episodes now but um
my podcast was kind of like trying to
help people go through the same thing as
me at the beginning you know uh I would
say a lot of my earlier episodes are I
mean they're cringe they're still
they're still available but I was to
learn how to talk to people else to
learn how to listen I was still learning
how to meet people where they're at and
not like force them into the corners of
you're on my show we're going to talk
about this you know that like there's
this there's this there's this balance
of sorts you know with these
conversations um and so I started
interviewing and talking to a lot of my
friends and um uh people in the
community and people that I looked up to
and I had a podcast Studio at that time
in my basement at the house that we had
so I could have them come over and it
was just this such cool thing you know
they would come over and um
we'd go for a walk or we would you know
uh you know smoke a bowl and hang out in
the backyard for a couple hours before
the podcast and it was just this very
very cool experience
um but but I had started it
the concept junkyard love is the name is
um
I had realized that when I was listening
to these people on YouTube and online
and audiobooks and these sorts of things
that
um they would unknowingly say something
that would completely shift my reality
you know two hours and 15 minutes into a
podcast of two comedians just bsing they
would say one thing one sentence in such
a certain way that would be primed to
for whatever reason that that I would
like pause the podcast and just go whoa
you know I would almost watch my reality
shift and I would allow that to enter
through me and go oh I haven't thought
about life like that I haven't
challenged my ideas like that you know
and so the concept is is sort of it
might be gibberish you know your story
might not seem important but when you
share it it might be really important to
somebody else you know the a uh the
example I use is you know a
90s 1996 Buick LeSabre uh passenger side
mirror is completely worthless to
somebody who doesn't have a 1996 Buick
LeSabre with a missing passenger side
mirror you know
um and so that was this kind of thing
it's like your story is very important
and there's something that you could say
about just communicating your truth that
could be profound to someone it could it
could change their whole life you know
and so so share you know share where
you're at and don't
um uh you know and you've you've
mentioned this in your videos too is
don't wait till you think you're ready a
lot of the times you know like make it
messy if it's messy if you stumble over
and you say like or you uh you know you
you you don't know exactly how to
explain your story but you kind of
stumble through it cool that's what it
is right there that that's okay
um that's why I started the podcast I
started at that time I'd already been a
DJ
you know say this is around you know 27
28 I'd already been DJ since I was like
19 20.
um
and I hadn't made a ton of my own stuff
so so being a DJ is
um
a lot of times you're playing
you're not really representing you you
know you're playing other people's music
you're mixing and mashing you're looking
around the room and you're seeing what
that room would want you're being a
taste maker you're on top of the current
music you anticipate people's needs
before they anticipate it you know
what's popular you know
um you know the the right the hottest
song in the world right now if you play
it at you know
10 21 it might suck but if you play it
at 11 38 PM it might be you might change
the entire room you know and so I was
just very
um I was on the pulse there's a lot of
ways that I was certainly an artist
as a DJ and I would create these
hour-long sets and I just wanted like my
DJ name at the time was Chronos DJ
Kronos who's the Greek Titan of time
and that was kind of bored of you know I
had experiences in crowds of music
festivals and stuff where time itself
would would skip or stop or um you know
I I think a good artist can make you
like you know snap out of time in in a
sense you know it's uh it could take you
to a place
um and and so I was really obsessed with
that sort of thing so my Artistry as a
DJ
um
was kind of I think it's different than
my Artistry now you know over the in the
last um
when I started my my Kundalini Awakening
healing journey I just kind of naturally
started outputting a lot of my own
writing and my own um spoken word
um there's a lot of stuff that I've
written and wrote that I'm like I don't
know who wrote that but they used my
body you know is this like the Muse
worked through me I seem to have put
myself in the right position and threw
out a couple Nets and you know I I
caught some jellyfish or something you
know and gave it gave them to the world
so
um I started kind of leaning a little
bit farther away from DJing
um being being less in bars and clubs
and these sorts of things I was super
sensitive to
um being being in bars and clubs late at
night
um you know you know we use the term
Spirits for alcohol uh I think that
you've discussed this as well and oh I
think you did it actually with your
recent podcast when he was talking about
alcohol
um I just became Ultra sensitive to
those things and so I kind of had this I
need to keep my Artistry you know I have
this need to to express myself I have
this something I you know something
inside me wants to communicate or
communicate through me
start doing more spoken word
um I've always been a fan of a fan of
hip-hop and those sorts of things so uh
I think there's like an innately I I
would hate to call myself a rapper I
just I think that sounds so so weird but
um I I do like I write a lot of rap
um but uh there's kind of like a
spiritual uh tendency to a lot of what I
write if you listen to it
um
I just want to invite our audience to uh
to check out your Instagram the links
will be in the description uh but we'll
keep going sorry to cut you off no no no
plug in there
I thank you yeah and I feel like
actually probably probably Instagram is
my best you know I have some songs on
Spotify I'd like to call everything a
demo um because you know although
although like I technically have an
audio engineering degree I won't just
sit and spend time like trying to mix
and master my stuff like for one it's a
lot of it is beyond my skill level you
know I don't know everything about all
this stuff
um but I like just like I said just
throw it out a net and like cool I
caught something let's share it you know
I like this Lo-Fi sort of um you know so
I have some stuff on Spotify it's it's
uh it's like sound art you know it's
there's this like kind of hip-hop but
um it's just kind of like a an
expression of of the thought that I seem
to have have caught
um but yeah my Instagram has certainly
been a
it's interesting man because we have
these
I don't know I mean maybe you
experienced this sorts of stuff too
Brett uh you know with Instagram and
podcasting is uh you you kind of
basically get put into a bubble or a
category you know it's like oh are you
trying to be an influencer you know are
you trying to
um uh
like are you trying to sell something
you know um but I've I've always tried
to keep it yeah I always try to keep it
to where it doesn't because that feels
icky to me you know like I've never had
advertisements on my podcast I've never
had um those sorts of things that feels
like it's instantly trying to sneak
like oh hey look how spiritual I am I'll
help you but also buy this thing that
pays my bills you know there's there's
an integration that I think is is you
know um
can be worked on but uh I just really
wanted it to feel feel authentic and so
um my Instagram is definitely that like
I try to treat it as
you know an expressive outlet and not as
I mean I want to be an influencer on
Instagram or I want to
um achieve this thing you know I've
never tried to sell anything
any of that so it's just been my
creative Outlet I really think that
um
I think that if you can penetrate people
in their day-to-day life as we're all
you know me for sure I have my
Tendencies to just scroll kind of
mindlessly you know it's something I'm
always I'm always struggling with
sometimes I do it too much sometimes I'm
on top of it
um but there are times where I'm
scrolling and somebody can say something
or like I can get this spoken word or I
can get this um clip from a podcast
that's just boom makes you suddenly
realize that like you're looking at your
phone and there's a background to your
phone and you're in a room and it just
kind of sends you out of your body in a
sense and I always really wanted my work
to do that in some ways I want my
my Artistry to be some sort of Co-op
Cohen you know a Zen Cohen of um
I wanted to put you in a place that you
weren't planning on going today you know
um and again just describing that sounds
very itself self grandiose uh but that's
kind of part of it you know that's a lot
of my with the the intertwining of my
spirituality and my Artistry is
not denying my ego not denying that like
you know not only you know nerves but
um
like like if I'm speaking to speak to
people on a stage or I'm speaking to
people uh you know okay I've got a
couple hundred people listening to this
podcast like that feels cool you know
noticing that like noticing that you
have like an ego side that you know for
me like I said I came from a background
of DJing where people know my name you
know like people in my hometown know me
as uh what up Chronos and like I don't
know who they are you know and and
there's a balance of uh for a while I
tried to kill the ego I tried to reject
it you know I tried to uh
like you know I gotta be next level
humble and and in all these things but
there's you know it seems your role as
an artist
um
is
is to behold the ego is to
um uh I have this line the ego doesn't
like change nor grit but loves to feel
withhold
um and so a lot of my a lot of my stuff
is kind of a balance of of uh working
with the ego you know ramdas would talk
about uh how on stage he would be
completely aware that um you know people
love him they seem as this is oh that's
you know but he's also just there to do
he's there to do his work you know parts
of him are going to notice those things
there's parts of us that I think
socially will
um uh
like those things but we can't Define
ourselves by
um this pedestal that other people put
us on in a sense so um
yeah
um I guess that's kind of like I try to
integrate my I try to live my philosophy
and my creativity and my Artistry as
naturally as I can you know I try to
you know if I go for a walk and I have a
thought come into my head that I think
is kind of cool or helpful or or fun I
want to share it you know but I'm not
trying to share it to accomplish
something I'm not trying to share it to
um uh you know gain more followers or or
um uh you know tell everybody how cool I
am you know it's it's this uh I try to
use social media as
a a a a genuine like tool for
communicating the inside of my mind in a
sense you know and I think that's like
active philosophy you know that's like
actually practicing philosophy
um and um yeah I don't know I think
sometimes you know as as we're scrolling
through when something real pops up we
note it as real you know there's all
these people trying to sell stuff
there's all these advertisements there's
all these um you know like
it's just obvious to us when you've got
a podcast like if I have a Monster
energy drink sitting right here and the
logo is perfectly faced you know that's
okay like a cool okay we'll get it
you're sponsored by monster but there's
just like this level of truth that we
want to be about that sort of thing you
know and I would hate for me having this
monster logo sponsorship to deter or or
change anything even one percent of how
I'm gonna communicate of the ideas that
I catch and communicate
um and so yeah it's just uh
I don't know my social media presence is
really like uh it's almost like this I'm
massively aware but it's almost like a
second ego in a sense right it's like
almost like this digital ego of
representing ourselves you know and we
talked about
um the beginning of your you know you're
into uh is it photography or videography
uh photography
photography yeah and you notice that you
know you have this photography page and
you start talking about spiritual stuff
on there and people are like
what yeah what are you talking about
dude uh it's a yeah I've gone through
that entirely that same thing of trying
to find this balance of living through
my truth of um
yeah I want to be an artist but like I'm
not creating this artist to get famous
and get money and like uh you know so I
can drive a fast car it's like no I I
want to be honest about every day I'm
trying to live as an artist I'm trying
to be as a poet would be in my
day-to-day life I'm trying to show up as
fully as I can
um and and be aware that I have these
different kind of aliases in a sense but
not lose myself into my Alias to where
I'm denying the truth of my being you
know because I think that's so easy to
do as an artist um I think you know you
know I was talking about the 27 club we
get so obsessed with our image like Oh
They'll they'll listen to me when I'm
gone you know that sort of thing and
it's it could just be certainly uh
massively toxic you know so uh I I I'm
sure that you maybe deal with some of
the similar things of um trying to
balance you know your personas in a way
I don't know do you ever
um
did you ever have any like debacle
between who you show up as you know like
who maybe your co-workers uh know you as
or who um I think you're doing some
schooling like maybe who they know you
as versus Brent Spirit
um do you ever feel any like trip up
between these kind of characters you've
created at all
yeah so
I think I've
a long time because uh you know like you
like you described uh in your own
Journey it's it's an ongoing sort of
dance and trying to figure it out and I
had my own issues with working as an
artist a photographer but then also
having these like spiritual things that
I wanted to express
and of course
um you know people that are interested
in my photography are like you know what
the hell is this guy talking about and I
think that came from a more ungrounded
place as well like we were describing
earlier that would you know get both
relate with just you know that that
feeling of having to like vomit out all
this spiritual stuff to who any whoever
would listen right so now I I found
peace by
compartmentalizing my two
um
I guess you could say brands or
identities but in particular I think
I've described this before Brent's
spirit is a character
when I'm sitting here in this chair
that's Brent's spirit and I I want
people to know that when I turn this off
I'm not brand Spirit I'm Brent like I'm
a normal guy like you know like uh eat
junk food like you know have awkward
conversations with people and think
about it later go why did I say that or
something you know like I'm a normal guy
and I just I want to make that clear
um at this point in in my
brand or whatever or this journey I'm
not too disclosing of my personal life
um because I don't
want it to be about me as much as it is
about uh
I love the way you describe the ideas
that I'm catching and and presenting
um and not so much about me but I do
recognize of course the validity of the
story in the background and so it's a
defined balance of of those two things
but I I can totally relate and I don't
know that many others can I think
along the lines of what you're saying
you know you're speaking as as uh as an
artist that's not
creating art as a means to an end to
become somebody or to sell something
it's it's for the end in itself
um and I as you're speaking I remember
this this is a key Concept in uh
bhagavad-gita
um where Krishna says you're entitled to
the work
that's your reward is the work itself
but the fruits of your labor that all
belongs to God
so you don't work thinking okay you're
gonna get paid or something you work so
presently in the moment and that is the
reward of the gift itself the creation
itself and paradoxically I think those
are the best artists you know they tend
to do well at some point they tend to
have some impact
um but then I was also thinking as you
were speaking that there are
I mean back before social media the idea
of being a poet and becoming like world
famous that was completely ludicrous and
so poets were poets because of poetry
or you know artists or artists because
that's what they had that's what the
Muse wanted them to do there was no
Instagram to post it on you know these
people maybe lived in a small little
village with
same 100 people that saw their painting
and that was it
um and so the reward I think was the art
itself
not uh you know the uh the accolades
that may come may or may not come and I
think that's a key theme and Stephen
pressfield's work like you were
describing um you know the the Muse uh
inspires you to create and that feels so
good in itself
and um
you know that seems to be uh
what I like to try and remind myself of
because I can also get caught up in
ideas of like you know I look at the
like oh how many views did this video
get and and how does it compare to the
last one and then I remember like
uh it's it's completely out of my
control it's completely something else
yeah
yeah where whereas you know if you had a
boss or you have a sponsorship that's
like hey your viewership is Down Like
You Don't Want to Lose Your sponsorship
right you know it's a it's kind of you
know I think in any artist or any
Creator who is who's using their
creative
um stuff to pay their bills I think
that's an easy thing to get caught in
um uh luckily I I have uh my my work in
Live Events is separated from a lot of
this work as much as I try to keep it
all kind of just like
um you know there's no secrets with me
there's no um you know like if somebody
on on the job side it's like hey if I
found your social media what's this all
about like I would love to tell them all
about it you know but like right now I'm
here you know oh you hired me to uh be a
lighting Tech today so that's who I am
you know
um uh but yeah I think uh I do find it I
do find it very interesting like the the
integration of uh
being an artist and
making sure everybody knows you're an
artist or like being treated as an
artist you know I think we see it with a
lot of famous people sometimes you know
we'll see videos or or Clips where
um
you know
like it kind of has this don't you know
who I am flavor to it which which is uh
uh
yeah man like uh I saw this video once
it was
I think it was Jay-Z on a subway and he
was talking to this old lady and she was
like asking what he does he's like oh
I'm a rapper and she's like oh you know
and she she's like oh I remember exactly
maybe she said liking my grandkids like
rapper or something and
um and basically she had never heard
about Jay-Z she doesn't know about Jay-Z
which you know to most of us is like
what you know about you know about Jay-Z
uh but dude all he is to her in that
moment is just a man on the subway and
like oh we're talking about working in
oh you rap that's pretty cool well
here's what I did in my life you know in
in I think we can get caught up in a
version of
you know like what if Jay-Z was offended
like you don't know who I am you know
and suddenly you can't you can't connect
with this person you know so uh yeah
yeah there's this way where we want to
take our Artistry with us
um you know whether you have fame or not
but there is kind of this um like trying
to introduce it you're trying to control
The Narrative of who you are you're
trying to control how people see you at
all times and I think that like a lot of
artists um get get caught up in this you
know and it's uh it's this it's the
stance of the ego um but but I I really
like just trying to
trying to be very natural and open and
honest about that integration you know
um uh I I had this example yesterday so
I think that even outside of people
knowing me as an artist or if they've
ever listened to any of my stuff or if
they've followed me or any of that
um it's been pretty cool over the last
couple years just to
you know I'm not trying to force any
sort of spiritual talk in anybody I'm
not trying to make anybody you know if
they want to talk about the the Family
Guy episode last night and I thought
cool I'd love to talk about that that
sounds fun let's laugh together and and
they don't have to know anything about
me being spiritual
um but it's actually very cool when you
relax that like need to like you know
hate what you want to don't you want to
heal your childhood trauma uh it seems
inevitably people notice what subject
areas uh you seem to be you know Wise or
intelligent about so yesterday I was on
this gig I actually um
it was I didn't even know until I got to
the gig but it was a private event for
the band One Republic down in San
Antonio and uh I only know that because
I didn't I didn't meet them or see them
or anything but we're pushing in the
cases and I saw their their name on the
thing
um but this younger guy who uh through
this company I'm a supervisor for for a
lot of their shows and uh
basically like as there's a lot of roles
where I'm I'm teaching um younger guys
you know like in their early 20s about
the world and about what we do and and
uh it's it's it's really cool because I
get to be kind of this uh leadership
role you know I really like being a
leader when I can and so I'm not only
teaching them about you know the correct
wires for this and the this is how this
runs and this is how we do this in this
world but um also just by my my me being
present and me being interested in
things that I'm interested in
um they notice that I'm knowledgeable or
or a person who who can give them you
know maybe good advice or something on
subject so in anyway last night this
this younger guy that
um that I've worked with who kind of
like asked me some inquisitive questions
I feel like he really listens when I
talk um so I try to take that serious it
seems like he actually does want to
learn something from me
um uh he was like man I'm so glad to see
you I've been meaning to tell you uh add
sleep paralysis the other night and then
I fell back asleep and he starts talking
about all this lucid dreaming stuff and
uh he is is so cool to me he sees me as
someone who is uh knowledgeable and
willing to speak about uh lucid dreaming
and the dream world and and then so we
kind of get into you know the whole gig
we're kind of talking about lucid
dreaming and all these really
interesting stuff and um he's
inquisitive to me
um and I'm just talking about things
that I'm generally interested in he's
asking me questions and I'm just telling
him truth like oh I read this book on
this and it seems like this thing sort
of happened so
um it I think to round about what I'm
trying to say is is that
when you just show up show up as who you
are rather than trying to run around
with a microphone tell or a megaphone
telling everybody that you are this
thing I think that opportunities to
be the expression of who you are and the
things that you're interested in
actually come about more often than you
may think
um wow well said
yeah
I was hoping that made sense
um but yeah it's a lot of my life these
days seems kind of like that like I just
try to you know I'm not meditating so I
can be an ultimate meditator in like
teach everybody I meet about meditation
but I meditate so I could be
a true Express expression of who and
what I am
and when other people
stop by and and they happen to need that
and here I am you know
it's it's like this um
and I yeah I I think you can get what
I'm quite I'm trying to point out
there's this level of being an artist of
being a a poet a Creator a content
creator an influencer where you're like
I'm this don't you want to hear about it
but it's like this is actually it's all
very spiritual being an artist is your
work
it's only your work and other people
don't don't have to give a crap about it
you know as great as it is to create
something and have other people see it
and have an audience and and there is
that that whole realm and that's amazing
but there's also a way in which you got
to be honest with yourself man if you're
obsessive about this philosophy
meditation stuff then be obsessed about
it like you don't have to run it run
around the streets and tell everybody
about it but I think that there's a
reason why
you there's only a reason for other
people in your relationships in your
life to for you to
um pursue your interests in such ways
but there's also a
you you'll begin to notice that
when people are trying to come up for
air there you are you know like you you
have the answers you weren't talking
about you weren't planning on talking
about those things that day or you
weren't reading this book so you could
go on and tell everybody about the
concepts in this book
um and if that's what you do if you have
a YouTube channel and that's what you do
like that's cool man that's you know
that's whatever but I think there's this
beautiful uh intertwining with Artistry
of this like artistic spirituality of
sorts that is you do your work and just
trust that
you are affecting the people around you
you know your audience is right right
just people in the street your
co-workers you know your family just the
presence that you bring because you do
your own work isn't about you walking
into the room of your family and going
you all need to meditate right now it's
about as they're screaming at each other
and you seem to be at peace like they
can't ignore that you know like you
they're going to start asking questions
in a sense you know
um so yeah it's just spirituality and
Artistry it's very personal man it's
very personal as much as it's performed
on the stage as much as it's given to
the world as much as it's presented in
this this sort of way it's a deep
personal work you know and it's almost
your job is a you you've spoken nicely
about
um uh a lot of like Kundalini stuff is
like spiritual puberty in a sense
in
it's kind of kind of a lot of what it is
it's like this your spirituality as an
artist I think is
a way of working on your maturity like
you're maturing into what's trying to be
communicated through you and um you know
getting obsessed with like how other
people think about you or or how you're
presented or um uh you know where your
work goes and all this sort of stuff
kind of gets in the way of your your own
personal work I don't know I I uh I
guess I'll kind of kind of round out
there but I think overall just the
intense personal nature of being an
artist is very important it's not about
other people it's not about it's not
really about the artist it's it's a very
um it's your own maturity trying to
trying to work through itself and I
think that you know there's ways that we
can be untruthful to the art if we're
trying to strangle it if we're trying to
hold it if we're trying to present it in
a certain way you know it's it's a I
don't know it's very personal
right I love the way you you you you say
that it is very personal spirituality
artistry
what's coming to me here is you know if
you're if you're in a relationship with
another person your relationship between
the two of you is also a personal thing
that you don't necessarily present to
the world whereas you know you may see
some celebrities
uh you know
whether it's stage or not but you know
they like have a TV show that
trades their relationship to the world
and it's now a public affair
whereas our relationship with our
spirituality our relationship with our
Artistry our art is personal it's
um and maybe some of it will leak out
into the public here and there but I
like the way you're describing that and
and going back to the way that you're
you're playing a sort of uh mentor
I don't know if that word feels right
for you but it sounds like that to me in
terms of when you're at work and whatnot
um I was thinking of asking you whether
you'd consider yourself a light worker
um this idea of like you know somebody
with with some sort of uh spiritual
intention
you know doing doing works of service
out in the world
um I'm interested to get your take on
that but it seems that you know you're
you're living your spiritual awakening
out in a very integrated way that
um is necessary at this time what I've
said before is that yeah I mean I play
this you know spiritual teacher and for
the most part those are the people that
we hear from who write books do videos
whatever and others go through Spiritual
Awakening and think well that must be
the only job that's there for me now is
to you know start being a spiritual
podcaster or something because we don't
hear so much from people that are like
yourself working in uh you know the
entertainment industry as a supervisor
supporting other people
uh to do their work and intertwined in
there you're throwing in some of the the
wisdom that you've gained along the way
and I think that's absolutely necessary
to get this Ascension going because we
can't all go on Retreats and leave our
jobs and and start you know like like
you did you know consuming hours and
hours of content every day and
meditating all the time some people
their sat song is uh you know on the job
wiring up some lights and speakers and
whatnot maybe that's what it is I'm
curious to get your take on that how
does that feel for you maybe I'm way off
would you consider yourself a light
worker
no yeah I really like how you pointed
that out I um I don't think lightworker
is a term that I use but obviously it's
in my uh vicinity you know I hear it all
the time and I I like it I like the way
you describe it I think um
yeah um
even before my spiritual stuff I've
always been a bit of a chameleon um I
can kind of assimilate to whatever
situation there's a lot of ways where I
think that kind of like my childhood
traumatic um you know I I basically
realized from a young age oh nobody's
taking care of me I've got to figure out
how people work I gotta figure out how
Society works I gotta figure out how to
like take care of myself and so I was
very observant of everybody I watch
everybody and I uh uh and I
you know you know my way of learning is
kind of like okay so people do that I
understand and then and then I would go
and act um
you know it's almost the birth the
birthplace of people pleasing in a lot
of ways too that's that's been a lot of
my journey is kind of unraveling that
but um uh my chameleon nature allows me
to connect with people
in a way that um
kind of like penetrates and reflects in
and um
so okay so so like if I'm describing a
chameleon nature there's you know say
there's two versions of us there's our
social self and then there's our
internal dialogue you know and a lot of
times people can be projecting or being
a chameleon of
the social self like if someone shows up
to me and they're like I'm this job and
I'm I'm a mom and I have this car and
that's like who they're trying to be and
who they're trying to uh interact with
me as
um I have this natural ability
it seems
um to
reflect back to you who you are
but not who the Persona is of who you
are it's almost like like sometimes
um
I I'd really try to come come across as
kind and sweet and you know I very much
love people
um but oftentimes I notice that I'm
triggering people by just
um like my I'm almost like reflecting
back to them something that they may be
thinking inside in in a sense
um and there is some sort of like
attraction to that in in some sort of
ways from other people like
it's almost like when someone is ready
for the truth they stumble on my path or
something like that
um and again that sounds like really uh
a big-headed uh but
um they're just like a way that
I will notice you know some some friends
that I've that have like told me this
but also just something that I've just
been observant of is um uh
I will speak to people in a way in which
nobody has ever spoken to them
I will
not just by the way that my subject like
you know certain subjects just don't get
talked about you know you don't you
don't talk about uh politics in in God
at the dinner table that sort of thing
um you know I'm like what are you
talking about like that's the most fun
you know let's talk about God that
sounds so fun you know
um
but I don't know yeah yeah there's a way
that I think that now that I'm aware of
it man I think that um
there is ways where just me being my
true self
does kind of
I don't know if I'm saying this right
but like it influences like there is
some Shock Depot there is there is
um spiritual things that happen within
other people
by having conversations with me
and I'm not really sure where to put
that you know you may have that that
might be not even just like a me thing
that might be uh anybody on the
spiritual path
it's like
I almost maybe accidentally like give
people little glimpses of something that
they didn't realize they were carrying
around or something or like like
um you know I think love and intimate
relationships can often show you this of
like
um uh you know they allow the truest
version of you to express itself and
that is so um so many layers deep behind
people sometimes
um and so yeah yeah I think in some
senses I would consider myself a light
worker again it's not super intentional
um
it's it's just my own work it's it's
right it's my own
you know what what we practice in
private is is what other people hear or
what uh there's some artist thing like
uh like
you're showing everybody something you
made in your dark basement you know like
I just go in my dark basement and I do
my work and
if you're willing to meet me there if
you're willing to meet me where you
really are and where I really am there
could really be some you know spiritual
energy exchanged you know whether we're
you know neither of us are trying to
have that thing I think intentionally
consciously anyway
um
but yeah yeah I'll have conversations
with people and I can tell or they will
tell me afterwards that they've never
had any sort of conversation like that
before and I'm like oh that's kind of
what I was thinking about that day you
know those sorts of things I don't know
if that really answers your light
workout question right no it's perfect
it's uh it's a perfect answer and I
think
we're approaching a topic there that
many out there going through something
so profound as Kundalini Awakening
are thinking it and feeling it and
experiencing it yes it does have an
impact on others this energy I like to
describe is contagious and that can
cause us to in the way you said you know
feel like you know we're getting a
little arrogant big-headed and we you
know we might want to even shut it down
or think how can I be influencing other
people or radiating something or they're
uh they're you know being attracted to
me and whatnot but let's get it out
there in the open yeah we're all
radiating every human being is radiating
this is science and the Heart emanates
and electromagnetic field our nervous
systems can co-regulate each other
um there is uh something unspoken that's
being transmitted now somebody who's
gone through something like uh you
described Spiritual Awakening Kundalini
Awakening the the Deep inner healing
they're radiating some component of that
um
and so yeah it happens but as long as we
are like like you we're saying I'm just
doing my work I'm just I'm just me I'm
not going around saying hey come to me
I'll change your life you're not saying
that hey I'll I'll blast your mind with
some cool line I have or some look in
your eye or something just doing you and
people come if they're in a position to
receive something from you you receive
it and and I'm sure others are are
you're receiving things from them I
receive things from other people as well
we're all exchanging information
um so I just love the way you're
describing this
um because I know many many on the path
are in fact the complete opposite of
what we may call a narcissist you're so
afraid of going in any direction that
may be uh uh uh you know in alignment
with some sort of arrogance and that
causes them to be like you know super
insecure small hide but no we have to
just come out and yeah if people are
meant to to pick up on something we have
to offer well let them let them pick up
on it and of course it doesn't happen to
everybody
um you know so people would say you know
SRI Ramana maharshi greatest Saint ever
you know
some people just looked at a photo of
him and it changed their life other
people in person just being in his
Fields experience incredible
spaciousness of peace but other people
are like well how's it what's the deal
with this this Indian guy wearing you
know it's a cloth as his underwear and
just sitting around like what the hell
is going on here you guys are right
it's not like he like said hey take a
picture of me and so when people see it
they get enlightened you know is it like
there's just a picture of him and
someone saw you know uh ramdas actually
just I just heard the talk I think
yesterday uh from ramdas how he was
talking about
um something that he would see saw in
this um I don't remember exactly some
like Christ movie um that he had seen I
don't know if his Passion of the
Chrysler or what exactly but um the way
that they were depict before he'd do a
miracle was like okay we need this
miracle done and he would stand in front
of it and go
and then like the miracle would happen
you know it is like he I love how he
describes that because he's like oh
that's not how it is you know it's it's
not a trying it's not a um
um it's it really is in a lot of ways is
you just being who you are getting out
of your own way in every moment and
allowing you know this this insane
spiritual energy to kind of work through
you and you know if someone is right for
it cool and if they're not right for it
they're gonna go like why are you
looking at this picture of an old half
naked dude with a blanket on like that
means nothing to me but um you know
again again with rhombus I know I talk
about him a lot but he's just I've been
uh a lot of his like heart centered work
has been really helpful for me
um but yeah it's it's a
I don't know man it's
it's a presence
I don't know I think it's very
fascinating like the word ripe that he
uses
now I wonder if you think about this
like the like what is it that makes you
know like if I'm sitting here with you
know say my best friend from childhood
and we've had a lot of similar
experiences we're a lot of like we're
best friends or whatever
and I'm listening to you on a podcast
and you say something and I'm like what
hold the pause it what that is the
craziest thing I've ever like my mind is
blown by it and he's like what why is
that important to you you know like what
is it that makes me so ripe to hear that
thing at that time
um in in
like I think that's rather fascinating
you know why is it that I had these
experiences you know
um there's studies about mystical
experiences where
um you know people who just live there
every day-to-day lives maybe they've
done psychedelics one time maybe they've
had um you know in a church setting
they've had like this profound what they
would call uh you know
a very important
part in their life like a very
life-changing reality altering moment in
their life some of us it could change
the trajectory of our entire life it
could change the course of everything
about us you know and that seems to be
what happens with us with Kundalini is
um you know we have these profound
experiential experiences this initial
kind of Awakening for some people they
could have this you know like I said my
best friend's sitting next to me or
something he could read the exact same
thing he could have the exact same thing
happening it's not about the words it's
about like the the the weaving of them
at the exact right moment you know you
have to be right for these sort of
things
um and I think
I don't know man is it it's just very
fascinating what do you think what is
that what is the like why are some of us
more ripe for these certain moments than
others in in what is the
uh I mean what are the what's the
Playbook here you know is like like a
koan could be so profound to me but
someone could listen to it and not hear
the same thing at all that I heard it's
just it's crazy yeah I think it's got a
lot to do with
um the uniqueness of this path
uh that we all have different things
that we're working out
um and one way I've described it is that
even right now there may not be
mind-blowing uh
conversation between you and I
but there's behind the scenes like
pieces are being laid
and at some point they're like the uh
the centerpiece will fall into place and
then it'll all
be a mind-blowing experience
um and so I I looked at it that way like
everybody
has a different pace that their Pieces
come into place
different different things different
themes and uh I think it makes it so
much more interesting otherwise this
path would be like super linear you know
be like okay everybody read this book
okay everybody read this poem listen to
this listen to this guys so this one
talk go to this time stamp and then you
know this is the book for for level 13
of Enlightenment is this book you can
read it in this grade yeah right and so
I think it just can it it shows that
this this path is so unique for us all
and that's why I I want to have guests
on like yourself you know you shared
such a unique journey and we all have
shared unique unique Journeys but some
people will resonate with some of the
major themes in yours and say ah the
other people didn't speak to me but
Jacob what he said that was a
centerpiece for me that was a a a click
for me when he said that
um and so I think that's how we all uh
support each other I'm I'm curious if uh
if if that's uh speaking to you or if
you've got anything else dad
no no entirely yeah yeah I mean it kind
of correlates right with what I was
saying you know like like like somehow
what I'm communicating or somehow what
you're communicating is that passenger
side mirror of a 1996 Buick LeSabre
whatever you know it's just just the
right part I was thinking about the um
a term I've used in my writing uh uh
that I had just looked back on my notes
uh is the bottom dropping out
um in a lot of like the spiritual
practice is just a continuously the
bottom dropping out and uh you know not
now it's it's a very exciting thing it's
like something you almost want and it is
there's almost like a desire for oh cool
I could have another Revelation you know
because because Awakening is not a
moment it's a continuous you're
consistently Awakening and um sometimes
it feels like you backpedal but then you
realize you hadn't and you're you know
this is whole it reminds me of what I
was visualizing when you were talking
Brent was um you know those uh had an
arcade those quarter machines where you
drop like a token or a quarter and
they're just going back and forth and if
you drop the right token or the right
quarter at the right spot and you angle
it just right it's going to push you
know
five to fifty Quarters off you know
um and sometimes they're just little
quarters being laid there's just little
tokens in our life that are
um you know being placed in the right
spot and they're stacking up but when
they drop out it's going to be a big
drop out you know right you're gonna win
big you know so
um yeah I think that's so fascinating I
love the
um
you know it it just seems like you know
rhombus uses the word ripeness or or you
you just ripe I mean I've heard other
other spiritual teachers use it too and
uh it's really just a reminder to follow
the the path for you or I'm sorry it's a
reminder to follow your path not
necessarily the path you know it's right
up there in line with your goal is not
to be a good meditator you know you're
not you're not supposed to be the best
meditator like I'm good at meditating
now I'm spiritual you know it's like
maybe that's not your path you know
maybe
um
maybe it's not about sitting down to
read the war of art maybe it's about
you're an extreme person who does things
um you got to go all in and so what you
need is to put headphones in and buy the
audiobook and run until you're finished
with the book you know it's just like we
all have
um uh
there's like there's a very personal
intuition for all of us you know it's
not like you're as much as you know we
talk about tapping into the Muse and
there's this this continuous kind of
collective unconscious that speaks to us
in a sense
um to use Carl Young's uh uh wordings of
collective unconscious but um there's a
very personal spiritual path for each of
us and it's it's like it's okay is the
thing your your personal spiritual path
is okay you know
maybe suddenly
you get this moment like me where you
realize that you've kind of been a
shitty person and you're not living to
your truth and the person that you know
served you well for a long time uh was
really great but suddenly this person
just does not serve who you who you want
to be in the future you know maybe you
realize that and the answer isn't to
sell your clothes buy white and orange
cloaks and join a Buddhist Monastery you
know maybe it's ah man I I've been
drinking 17 beers a night like I'm gonna
only drink 16 tomorrow you know that's
an extreme example but it really is like
you gotta step on the path where you're
at you can't as much as we could use
other people's lives and their stories
and their Journeys as as influences and
inspiration and all this stuff
um you know I think that's been a huge
thing for me is is learning that my path
is okay you know my my spiritual journey
is personal and that's okay you know and
and I can't do it the way that other
people did it I tried to read this
um
forget that oh uh have you heard of the
term in meditation stream entry
right
yeah
um it's kind of like a step-by-step
process this is actually fun like it's
we're describe it's like a step-by-step
process for like
um uh reaching samadhi and stuff like
there's I think it's something like it's
like a ten step anyway I bought this
book
um in in the throes of me being obsessed
with with all this stuff and meditation
and I bought this book uh John caldasa I
think is his name one of the authors
um and man I remember just like trying
to push myself push myself okay I got to
meditate for this long each day it says
to do this I'm gonna do this meditation
um when in actuality like maybe what I
needed was to just
walk outside in the morning and pull up
YouTube and just click on whatever like
oh that seems like a cool meditation I'm
gonna do my meditation today you know
um
yeah yeah so so anyway I guess just like
um just believing our own personal
spiritual paths and stepping on it where
we're at you know maybe we're a hundred
miles from the path so we think but you
know
walking north towards the path if it's
north is better than walking South you
know uh so yeah so just walk in the
direction of what your spiritual path is
I think is what I'm trying to say here
oh well said I think many will will
resonate with that and find some some
peace and acceptance of where they're at
because of course
you know uh sometimes people think
they're doing something wrong or that
they're messing it up and because their
path doesn't look like someone else's
path
um I think it was I just Shanti who
like you also had a very uh I guess you
could say masculine approach to just
going at it meditating really intensely
and trying to make it trying and this
was the same for me I I was very
masculine in my Approach uh early on and
I deshanty describes and I can also
agree it
he says it's his spiritual path was was
one of failure it just all of his
efforts failed
um he may use the term I'm not sure but
I like to say I became exhausted by
those ever like I was so exhausted and
that's when shifts happen when I just
burnt myself out
um and that was my path when I look back
on one level we could say well that was
the incorrect approach but maybe
trying really hard was the approach for
us to get us to exhaust ourselves out so
it's paradoxical
um we can't get it wrong even if
even if you are trying to like you said
you know get on the path where you're at
you know be true to your own Journey
even if there's somebody out there who's
trying to
copy another Journey or following a book
or tradition to the T
that's still their Journey too
you see it's like it's it's paradoxical
it's interesting but ultimately I think
you've shared some incredible wisdom
there you know we can't get it wrong
everybody has to get on the path where
they're at that's going to look
different and that's
really my intention with having guests
on this show is to show people that look
I can present my story my ideas in my
own way but I don't want it people to
listen to me as if that's the only way
and so of course uh you know we've got
guests on like Jacob to share
your story that looks so unique and
different but of course if we
extrapolate there are the overarching
themes
of uh introspection practicing presence
getting back into the body getting back
into the world
um you know living a real life paying
bills
healing you know healing the inner child
uh all of those things have come up
today and it's been an excellent
excellent conversation Jacob um it's
about time that we start to wrap up but
uh I want to thank you for sharing so
openly and such a a real way that I
think is going to really speak to a lot
of people and people will say hey yeah
you know
I'm
I I can accept my journey as it is
because uh you know we've got some
inspiration from you so thank you so so
on that note please let us know how we
can uh further connect with you
um all the links will be in the
description but please feel free to uh
shamelessly tell us about what you've
got going on online and how people can
uh tune in and listen to more of what
you have to say
um yeah yeah like I said at the
beginning I get to talk about myself my
favorite thing
um yeah man we'll we'll thank you Brant
so much uh you know I've appreciated our
interactions in our in our conversations
very greatly uh I'm really just I'm a
fan of your work so it's really cool for
us to be able to actually interact and
you know kind of you know we get to know
each other a little bit so I think it's
very cool I think it's very cool that
you're offering this space for people
um
you know dude it's such a
it's such a we've talked about this
before it's such an alienating
alienating journey and you do feel you
feel wonky man this this whole thing is
just just crazy whether you use the
terminate terminology of Kundalini or
even if you use the word spirituality or
whatever you know we're going to stumble
into our books and our learnings of of
what wordings and stuff make sense to us
you know maybe it's through a certain
religion maybe it's through
um you know healing from that religion
you know maybe that religion harmed you
when you were younger and you're trying
to find spirituality after that as an
adult there's all these different levels
of it and so yeah I think it's very
important and very cool that you offer
space for
um you know all of us on in in different
in different levels and different paths
and there's no it's normally wrong or
right way it's just kind of about
listening to your intuitive uh intuitive
way of guidance and
um yeah I I just I'm really just a fan
of your show I just love listening to
spiritual conversations anyway
um I love hearing when people Express
themselves uh how they're going through
certain things or they've been through
that and remember oh dude I had that
happen too that's actually pretty crazy
you know and uh it all correlates so
yeah man thank you so much but um yeah
so I would say probably these days
Instagram is is the best way to get a
hold of me Jacob from the internet
um and that is just I try to post my
podcast Clips on there with guests I try
to post
um poetry spoken word
um like I said I do some hip-hop stuff
I'll do some DJ work I have like all
these different facets of my creative
Journey that you know sometimes I'm
sometimes I have four months of just
like hard DJing you know and that's what
I'll be posting sometimes I have um
moments of being very introspective
sometimes I'm going through another like
Awakening layer and so I'm trying to
share that I try to be vulnerable on
there uh you know like I said I have
podcast episodes that are that are like
just cringy to listen back to but it's
just where I was at that time and so
that's just okay
um Jacob from the internet on Instagram
um the junkyard love podcast wherever
you listen to podcasts
um I believe my YouTube channel is uh
Jacob from the internet either way the
junkyard love podcast or Jacob from the
internet you will find me
um and I'm always just kind of sharing
um you know
I am known to like suddenly realize I
need a break from all this stuff and so
maybe I'll drop off the face of the
Earth for for a month or two on on
social media but for the most part I
like to post
um you know I like to share my story my
thoughts I like to share on my Instagram
and things that I'm thinking about or my
poetry or things that I've found in the
world like if I'm listening to your
podcast Brent and there's just this
magical 23 seconds of you saying
something I'm gonna share that to my
story I think that's super cool so yeah
I just tried to uh I'm genuinely
interested in spirituality and
self-growth and all this stuff and so
when I find little bits and pieces of it
I like to share that on my Instagram
story and my in my Instagram so yeah man
right right so all of the links will be
in the description to uh the junkyard
love podcast or Instagram YouTube I
invite everybody to check it out on your
podcast you've got uh some some of my I
think you call them solo cast where
where you speak about uh you know your
journey uh you had a talk about your
mental health experiences
um experiences with uh
I guess uh cutting out addictions and or
addictive uh things you know um for some
time and whatnot and and all very very
fascinating as well as you've got some
great guests on as well and yeah you
give them uh a platform to share and and
explore and uh I think even some
conversation with some friends too so
invite everybody to check out the
junkyard love podcast Jacob it's been an
absolute pleasure today thank you so
much if anybody's got a question for
Jacob about his journey can leave a
comment below on the YouTube or of
course get in touch and I'll invite you
Jacob to uh jump in the comments to
respond to anybody that has uh anything
for you so with all that said thank you
so much Jacob to our listeners our
audience thank you so much for hanging
out with us today we really appreciate
you and until next time much love
and peace
peace
cool we are recording
yeah I hope I hope it was a bit clearer
the rant is always interesting to talk
about yourself in uh you know like I was
saying I've been thinking about how do I
want to present myself how do I want to
present my journey I actually didn't
want to talk about the cocaine thing
because I feel like it it just feels
icky you know but it uh you know maybe
maybe it's what somebody needs to hear
so it sounds like that's what needed to
come out I suppose hello and welcome to
the junkyard love podcast
foreign
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]